[{"show": "q", "color": "color2", "question": "obdurate anti-colonialism, in Bernard Fall's view, led to cold refusal of American aid for [], and to a policy of ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "French resistance fighters; promoting Ho Chi Minh and the Viet Minh as the alternative to restoring the French bonds", "id": 1},{"show": "q", "color": "color0", "question": "Fall: \"The United States, preoccupied in Europe, ceased to be a diplomatic factor in Indochina until [] in []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the outbreak of the Korean War.\" ; 1950", "id": 2},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "Other commentators..have described U.S. policy as consistently []  the reimposition of French colonial power in Indochina", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "condoning and assisting", "id": 3},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "the United States was less []over Indochina, and less [] than either assumes", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "concerned , purposeful ", "id": 4},{"show": "q", "color": "color2", "question": "On the one hand, the U.S. repeatedly reassured the French that ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "its colonial possessions would be returned to it after the war.", "id": 5},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "On the other band, the U.S. broadly committed itself in the Atlantic Charter to", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "support national self-determination, ", "id": 6},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": "and President Roosevelt personally and vehemently ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "advocated independence for Indochina. ", "id": 7},{"show": "q", "color": "color0", "question": "The President discussed [] with the Allies at []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": " a trusteeship ; the Cairo, Teheran, and Yalta Conferences ", "id": 8},{"show": "q", "color": "color0", "question": "he received the endorsement of ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "Chiang Kai-shek and Stalin; ", "id": 9},{"show": "q", "color": "color2", "question": "[] demurred.", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "Prime Minister Churchill", "id": 10},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": " At one point, Fall reports, the President offered General de Gaulle [] to help France establish a \"more progressive policy in Indochina\"--which offer the General received in \"Pensive Silence.\"", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "Filipino advisers", "id": 11},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "Ultimately, U.S. Policy was governed by ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the dictates of military strategy and by British intransigence on the colonial issue.", "id": 12},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": "The United States, concentrating its forces against [], accepted British military primacy in Southeast Asia, and divided Indochina at [] between  [] for the purposes of occupation. .", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "Japan, 16th parallel , the British and the Chinese ", "id": 13},{"show": "q", "color": "color2", "question": "U.S. commanders serving with the British and Chinese, while instructed to avoid ostensible alignment with the French, were permitted ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "to conduct operations in Indochina which did not detract from the campaign against Japan. ", "id": 14},{"show": "q", "color": "color5", "question": "U.S. did provide modest aid to  [] resistance forces in Vietnam after March, 1945, but refused to []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "French--and Viet Minh-- ; provide shipping to move Free French troops there", "id": 15},{"show": "q", "color": "color0", "question": " Pressed by both the British and the French for clarification U.S. intentions regarding the political status of Indochina, F.D.R- maintained that ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "\"it is a matter for postwar.\"", "id": 16},{"show": "q", "color": "color5", "question": "The President's trusteeship concept foundered as early as [], when the U.S. discovered that the British, concerned over possible prejudice to Commonwealth policy, proved to be unwilling [], and indeed any statement endorsing national independence which went beyond []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "March 1943,  to join in any declaration on trusteeships,  the Atlantic Charter's vague \"respect the right of all peoples to choose the form of government under which they will live.\"", "id": 17},{"show": "q", "color": "color2", "question": "So sensitive were the British on this point that [], at which the blueprint for the postwar international system was negotiated, skirted the colonial issue, and avoided [] altogether ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the Dumbarton Oaks Conference of 1944 ; trusteeships", "id": 18},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": "At each key decisional point at which the President could have influenced the course of events toward trusteeship--in relations with the U.K., in [], in --he declined to do so; hence, despite his lip service to trusteeship and anti-colonialism, F.D.R. in fact assigned to Indochina a status correlative to []: free territory to be reconquered and returned to its former owners", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "casting the United Nations Charter ; instructions to allied commanders ;  Burma, Malaya, Singapore and Indonesia", "id": 19},{"show": "q", "color": "color0", "question": "Non-intervention by the U.S. on behalf of the Vietnamese was tantamount to", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "acceptance of the French return", "id": 20},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "On [], with President Roosevelt's approval, Secretary of State [] issued a statement that, as a result of the Yalta talks, the U.S. would look to trusteeship as a postwar arrangement only for [] and for []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "April 3, 1945, Stettinius, \"territories taken from the enemy,\"  \"territories as might voluntarily be placed under trusteeship.\" ", "id": 21},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "Shortly following President Truman's entry into office, the U.S. assured France that ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "it had never questioned, \"even by implication, French sovereignty over Indo-China.\"", "id": 22},{"show": "q", "color": "color2", "question": "With British cooperation, French military forces were reestablished in South Vietnam in ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "September, 1945", "id": 23},{"show": "q", "color": "color0", "question": "Through [], the U.S. received a series of requests from Ho Chi Minh for intervention in Vietnam; these were, on the record, unanswered. ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the fall and winter of 1945-1946", "id": 24},{"show": "q", "color": "color2", "question": "the U.S. steadfastly refused to assist the French military effort, e.g., ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "forbidding American flag vessels to carry troops or war materiel to Vietnam", "id": 25},{"show": "q", "color": "color5", "question": "On [] the French and Ho signed an Accord in which Ho []  in return for []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "March 6, 1946, ; acceded to French reentry into North Vietnam ; recognition of the DRV as a \"Free State,\" part of the French Union", "id": 26},{"show": "q", "color": "color5", "question": "As of [], allied occupation of Indochina was officially terminated, and the U.S. acknowledged to France []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "April 1946 ; that all of Indochina had reverted to French control", "id": 27},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "In [], the Franco-Viet Minh War began in earnest.", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "late 1946", "id": 28},{"show": "q", "color": "color0", "question": " The U.S. in its representations to France deplored the prospect of protracted war, and urged []. However, the U.S., deterred by the history of [], always stopped short of [].", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "meaningful concessions to Vietnamese nationalism ;  Ho's communist affiliation ; endorsing Ho Chi Minh or the Viet Minh", "id": 29},{"show": "q", "color": "color5", "question": "U.S. policy gravitated with that of France toward ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the Bao Dai solution", "id": 30},{"show": "q", "color": "color5", "question": "At no point was the U.S. prepared to adopt an openly interventionist course. To have done so would have clashed with the expressed [] view that Indochina was an exclusively French concern, and played into the hands of [].", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "British ; France's extremist political parties of both the Right and the Left", "id": 31},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "Beginning in 1946 and 1947, France and Britain were moving toward [] and the U.S. was reluctant to press a potentially divisive policy.", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "an anti-Soviet alliance in Europe ", "id": 32},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "It is not as though the U.S. was not prepared to act in circumstances such as these. For example, in [], the U.S. actively intervened against its Dutch ally. In this case, however, the intervention was in concert with [] and against the Netherlands", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the 1945-1946 dispute over Dutch possessions in Indonesia ; the U.K.", "id": 33},{"show": "q", "color": "color0", "question": "at the time, Indochina appeared to many to be one region in the troubled postwar world in which ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the U.S. might enjoy the luxury of abstention.", "id": 34},{"show": "q", "color": "color2", "question": "In [], early in the war, the U.S. Ambassador in Paris was instructed to reassure [] of the \"very friendliest feelings\" of the U.S. toward France and its interest in supporting France in recovering its economic, political and military strength:", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "February, 1947 ; Premier Ramadier ", "id": 35},{"show": "q", "color": "color5", "question": "Increasingly, the U.S. sensed that [] heightened the possibility of the Franco-Viet Minh conflict being transformed into [].", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "French unwillingness to concede political power to Vietnamese ;  a struggle with Soviet imperialism", "id": 36},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": "France was notified that the U.S. was willing to extend financial aid to [] not []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "a Vietnamese government ;  a French puppet", "id": 37},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "As of [], however, the U.S. remained uncertain that Ho and the Viet Minh were in league with the Kremlin", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "1948", "id": 38},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "In [], [] conducted a survey of communist influence in Southeast Asia. Evidence of [] was found in virtually all countries except Vietnam:", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the fall of 1948 ; the Office of Intelligence Research in the Department of State ; Kremlin-directed conspiracy", "id": 39},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": "To date [] have not adopted an anti-American position. It is rather [] that has been strongly anti-American and has freely accused the U.S. of imperialism in Indochina to the point of approximating the official Moscow position. ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the Vietnam press and radio ;  the French colonial press ", "id": 40},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "[] sharpened American apprehensions over communist expansion in the Far East, and hastened U.S. measures to counter the threat posed by []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "The collapse of the Chinese Nationalist government in 1949 ; Mao's China.", "id": 41},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "Thus, in [], the course of U.S. policy was set to block further communist expansion in Asia: by [] if the Asians were forthcoming; by [], if possible; but [] if necessary.", "difficulty": 5, "answer": " the closing months of 1949 ; collective security ; collaboration with major European allies and commonwealth nations ; bilaterally ", "id": 42},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "On that policy course lay [], [], and [].", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the Korean War of 1950-1953 ; the forming of the Southeast Asia Treaty Organization of 1954 ;  the progressively deepening U.S. involvement in Vietnam", "id": 43},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "[], were pivotal months. The French took the first concrete steps toward transferring public administration to []. Ho Chi Minh denied the legitimacy of the latter, proclaiming the DRV as the \"only legal government of the Vietnam people,\" and was formally recognized by []. ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "January and February, 1950 ; Bao Dai's State of Vietnam ; Peking and Moscow", "id": 44},{"show": "q", "color": "color5", "question": "Secretary of State [] made the following public statement: The Soviet acknowledgment of this movement should remove any illusions as to the \"nationalist\" nature of Ho Chi Minh's aims and reveals Ho in his true colors as ", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "Acheson ; the mortal enemy of native independence in Indochina.", "id": 45},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "In the interval between [], and [], the United States watched with increasing apprehension the flux of Japanese military power into Indochina.", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "the fall of France in 1940 ; the Pearl Harbor attack in December, 1941", "id": 46},{"show": "q", "color": "color4", "question": "that [] gives a clear indication of our intentions and activities for the future.", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "our Fleet is now based on Hawaii", "id": 47},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": " In [], however, Japan went beyond the use of bases to []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "1941  demands for a presence in Indochina tantamount to occupation.", "id": 48},{"show": "q", "color": "color1", "question": "from the military standpoint, the President said, surely the Japanese Government could not have in reality the slightest belief that [] had any territorial designs on Indochina nor were in the slightest degree providing any real threats of aggression against Japan", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "China, Great Britain, the Netherlands or the United States", "id": 49},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": "The same date, Secretary of State [] instructed Sumner Welles to see the Japanese Ambassador, and \"Make clear the fact that the occupation of Indochina by Japan possibly means one further important step to seizing control of the South Sea area, including trade routes of supreme importance to the United States controlling such products as [] and other commodities.\"", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "Cordell Hull ;  rubber, tin", "id": 50},{"show": "q", "color": "color3", "question": "In a press statement of [], Acting Secretary of State Welles deplored Japan's \"expansionist aims\" and impugned []", "difficulty": 5, "answer": "2 August 1941 ; Vichy", "id": 51}]